Contact

+40743960318 (Home) antonel.pazargic@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/antonelernest-pazargic-997bb25 (LinkedIn) bvb.ro/ (Company)

Top Skills

Azure DevOps Services Functional Programming Kotlin

Languages

English

Certifications

Functional Programming Principles in Scala

Reactive Architecture: Building Scalable Systems - Level 2

Reactive Architecture: Domain Driven Design - Level 2

Oracle Certified Professional, Java SE 8 Programmer

Lightbend Java Language Futures - Level 1

Antonel-Ernest Pazargic

Senior Software Developer at ING Tech Romania

Bucharest, Bucharest, Romania

Summary

I am a senior software developer with over 17 years of experience. I am passionate of

- programming languages (kotlin, scala, java),
- concurrent programming,
- enterprise application development,
- microservices,
- object oriented programming and, recently,
- functional paradigms and reactive architecture/systems.

I have extensive experience in all aspects of the software development life-cycle and I strive to approach every single phase of it in the most professional manner.

I am a code clean development and software craftsmanship enthusiast and a true believer in the evidence of "the code is way more read than write".

I always strive to stay up to date with the latest technologies, programming languages, methodologies and frameworks which could bring values to projects I work on.

The things that I found very interesting are Spring Boot (which allows to easily configure a spring frameworks and microservice-based application), Kotlin|Arrow FP Effects, Scala, Akka (distributed services), (Test)containers (Docker), Cloud (Spring Cloud, Netflix OSS).

Experience

ING Hubs Romania Software Developer March 2017 - Present (7 years 1 month) Bucharest, Romania

Design, develop, document, test and release REST microservices (part of the OAuth2 granting flow).

Technological stack:

- Spring projects/frameworks (core, boot, Web/MVC, AOP)

- Reactive programming with Akka, RxJava, Kafka
- Security (OAuth2, JWT, SSL)
- Kotlin (coroutines), Java, Python, Scala
- Testing: kotest, junit, springtest, BDD
- Performance testing: gatling (scala)
- Build tools: gradle, apache maven
- CI: Microsoft ADO
- Issue management: Service NOW
- SERE: Jackson|XML
- JavaFX/TornadoFX
- IDE: JetBrains Idea, VS Code
- Documentation: Atlassian Confluence
- VCS: git (Microsoft ADO)
- Metrics: Grafana, Graphite
- Logging: logback, log4j
- DevOp: Vagrant, Docker, Microsoft ADO (pipelines)
- Cloud: Spring Cloud (Ribbon, Feign), OpenShift, Kubernetes

Development methodology: agile (scrum)

Mentoring colleagues through internal presentations.

Presenter - Kotlin User Group Bucharest on meetup.com

European Commission

Application Architect

June 2014 - April 2016 (1 year 11 months)

My responsibilities consisted of:

- Collaborate with business analysts and customers for establishing the software requirements (my role was to identify some possible implementation difficulties which could impact the delivery time, and together find some alternatives)
- Implement the business requirements.
- Author the unit and integration tests
- Support the DevOp during the deployment
- Collaborate with other development teams/streams in order to integrate with different systems
- Author some POCs to establish the technologies/architecture of the green field project or for improving the existing applications
- Maintain and improve the existing applications.
- Perform code review
- Collaborate with the other roles in our team (Deployment Responsible, QA team member, Team Leader, the other Developers)

Main technologies used:

- java SE
- java EE Oracle Weblogic 12.1.3 (JPA, JMS, EJB, JSR 303, JAX-RC, JAX-WS/SOAP)
- IntelliJ Idea IDE
- unit testing (junit)
- Arquillian integration testing (dbunit)
- scala language and scala test frameworks (ScalaTest, ScalaMock,

ScalaCheck unit and integration testing

- mocking with Mockito
- project management with maven
- object mapping with dozer
- Oracle DB
- Code review with Atlasian Crucible
- Continuous Integration with Atlassian Bamboo
- Documentation/Wiki with Atlassian Confluence
- Jira defects tracking system
- Subversion versioning control
- Liquibase DB tool for database for generating the database schema, updating it and versioning.
- Javascript, npm, bower, gulp, RequireJS, Jasmine and AngularJS (entry level)

My accomplishments:

- Implement the validation framework
- Improve the testing by integrating scala testing frameworks
- Integrations with different systems such as Enterprise FullText Search, Document Management System
- Author a POC, for a greenfield project, which consisted of javascript technologies and frameworks: gulp, bower, npm, AngularJS, RequireJS, AngularJS, test frameworks (Karma, Jasmine)

1&1 Internet Development SRL
Senior Java Developer
June 2011 - November 2013 (2 years 6 months)

Design, develop and maintain a suite of software products about integration of current Do It Yourself state of the art product with social media providers (Facebook, Twitter).

Develop and deploy (in applications store) web applications (widgets) for a Webdesk dashboard.

My responsibilities require advanced knowledge about:

- object oriented programming,
- pattern driven development,
- java standard edition,
- IntelliJ Idea and Eclipse IDE
- unit, integration and functional testing,
- continuous integration (Jenkins),
- servers (tomcat, jetty) configuration,
- SQL (MySQL),
- caching,
- java for enterprise (Spring),
- distributed programming (REST, SOAP),
- building tools (maven),
- agile methodologies,
- software craftsmanship,
- multi-tire architecture,
- (programming and enterprise) design patterns,
- security (authentication, authorization, validation, sanitization and anonymization),
- transactions (ACID, CAP),
- REST-ful architectural style,
- Aspect Oriented Programming (AspectJ, Spring AOP),
- Object/Relation Mapping persistence with JPA2 and Hibernate,
- Source Control Management (Subversion and Subversive Eclipse plugin),
- groovy language (+ gspock specification testing),
- team working,
- good collaboration with ITOps team members,
- good collaboration with software architect, QA team members, requirements engineer, product owners,
- mentoring new members,
- good collaboration with other stream,
- willing to learn and strive for self-improvement,
- code review,
- code quality (SONAR, FindBugs, Cobertura, Code Style, PMD), medium knowledge about:

- NOSQL (Redis and Nio4J),
- functional testing with Selenium,
- python language,
- bash scripting,
- linux,
- http protocol,

and basic knowledge about:

- php, javascript, css, jquery,
- phing, css.

Freescale Semiconductor Romania

Senior Java Developer

March 2010 - March 2011 (1 year 1 month)

Design, develop and maintain a first-class C/C++ Development Suite, using Java SE 5+, Eclipse technologies (Plugins, PDE/PDE-build, Databinding, Resources API, Jobs API, P2), JUnit.

Bucharest Stock Exchange, Romania

Senior Java Developer

July 2008 - March 2010 (1 year 9 months)

Develop a client-server application using Eclipse technologies (RCP, Equinox OSGi RI, EMF, BIRT, EclipseLink, PDE, PDE-Build, P2), Eclipse Apache Mina and PostgreSQL.

Keba Automation

Senior J2EE Development Engineer

May 2008 - July 2008 (3 months)

Design and develop a client-server application using Java SE 5+, Spring framework 2.5, Swing, Hibernate ORM, Intellij Idea.

Alvarion

Senior Java Development Engineer

February 2007 - May 2008 (1 year 4 months)

S.C. IQBYTE S.R.L.

Java Senior Developer

April 2006 - February 2007 (11 months)

Involved in designing, development, testing and deployment of software services to health-care domain

S.C. Agress Business S.R.L.
Java Developer
May 2004 - April 2006 (2 years)
Involved in development of an ERP solution

Selir S.R.L. J2EE Developer 2003 - 2004 (1 year)

Education

Lower Danube University of Galaţi, Romania Bachelor of Science, Mechanical Engineering · (1993 - 1998)